<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mental-health on Amanda Park</title>
    <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/tags/mental-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mental-health on Amanda Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanda-park.github.io/tags/mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To: Practice Cognitive Defusion</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-27-cognitive-defusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-27-cognitive-defusion/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes our brains can ruminate endlessly on narratives we&amp;rsquo;d rather not listen to on a regular basis. A technique to try and soothe these concerns is cognitive defusion. Note: defusion will not necessarily make the thoughts go away and make you feel better. You need to accept thoughts and not try to control/repress them.
However, in general it has helped me. Some exercises that can be used to defuse thoughts are below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dangerous Impact of Social Media</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-24-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-24-social-media/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve become increasingly unimpressed with the impact of social media on our lives. I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself happier using online platforms on a limited basis, so I figured it&amp;rsquo;d be worth talking about why I&amp;rsquo;ve reduced my social media usage so much over the past few years.
It&amp;rsquo;s Designed to be Addictive The goal of mainstream social media apps in 2020 is to keep your attention on the screen for as long as possible, in what is now known as the attention economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Stay Grounded Mentally</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-05-grounding-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-05-grounding-techniques/</guid>
      <description>With the state of the world still being what it is, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to feel disconnected from our bodies. Grounding is a very important practice that we should all use on a regular basis, even when we&amp;rsquo;re not living through history. Below I’ll list a few of my favorite techniques I&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past to stay in the present moment (these can be done in quick succession or separately, depending on personal preferences):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Practice Psychological First Aid</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-03-psychological-first-aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-03-psychological-first-aid/</guid>
      <description>The goal of providing psychological first aid is to provide acute assistance to someone in crisis. It is a useful skill to have in any day and age, but the uncertainty of our current world makes it more critical than ever. George S. Everly, who works at Johns Hopkins, developed an empirically-based model called RAPID as a framework for people such as first responders to follow. Coursera was offering free certificates for certain classes due to COVID-19, so I decided to go ahead and check this one out.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
