<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome! on Amanda Park</title>
    <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome! on Amanda Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanda-park.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tips to Write More Effectively</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2021-02-10-quick-writing-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2021-02-10-quick-writing-tips/</guid>
      <description>When I was completing my undergraduate degree, I was known for having strong writing skills. Even if I hated writing essays, I could make a persuasive argument and get the A I wanted.
However, after attending grad school and now being in the workforce, writing a piece that was at least 8 pages and had many sources to back up its argument isn&amp;rsquo;t valuable.
Instead, focused and technical writing prowess is valued.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Obtaining the COVID Vaccine</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2021-01-26-covid-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2021-01-26-covid-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>Right now I&amp;rsquo;m especially grateful to have a job in healthcare. There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of work around regarding the approved COVID-19 vaccines, but with the essential nature of the work, healthcare workers (regardless of whether they are patient-facing nor not) have been prioritized to get the vaccine at my company.
As of today, I have two doses of the Pfizer vaccine injected in my arm. I believe in science and the efficacy of the vaccines, so I had no hesitation getting the shot at the moment it was offered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Committing to Spending Less Time on Social Media</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2021-01-03-reduce-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2021-01-03-reduce-social-media/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve previously made a post about the dangers of social media, which can be seen here. But this post is of a different flavor.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t explicitly talked about this, but in the past, I was addicted to social media. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t ever limited to one social media site, either. Throughout the 2010s, I had phases where I was addicted to a combination of the following at any one time:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on 2020</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-12-18-reflecting-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-12-18-reflecting-2020/</guid>
      <description>2020 was a year that threw us all for a loop, to say the least. Many of us had our lives as we knew it upended in some day due to the Coronavirus, and no matter what happens, we won&amp;rsquo;t be going back to how things used to be. Given how much has happened this year, I felt it fitting to reflect on some of the things I have accomplished this year and what I hope to accomplish in the next one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Wish I Knew About R Sooner</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-11-22-r-programming-wish-knew-sooner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-11-22-r-programming-wish-knew-sooner/</guid>
      <description>I was officially exposed to the programming language R when I enrolled in my graduate program in 2017. Three years have passed, and now I feel much more comfortable navigating R than I did when I first started. The way I learned R was very bumpy, and looking back there were a lot of ways I could have improved and expedited developing my skills in the language. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d write about this for anyone also interested in becoming proficient in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Lifelong Learning</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-11-15-lifelong-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-11-15-lifelong-learning/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve read some of my posts you&amp;rsquo;ll know that I&amp;rsquo;ve used online learning tools such as Coursera in the past to learn about topics of interest to me. Being in the field of data science, I know that the best tools for tackling challenging problems are constantly evolving, so it&amp;rsquo;s basically a must that I continue to learn about new findings in the ever-expanding field of data analytics.
One thing my organization did recently that I am incredibly grateful for is offering unlimited access to a site called LinkedIn Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in Game Development: First Game Progress</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-11-14-game-dev-first-game-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-11-14-game-dev-first-game-progress/</guid>
      <description>I know I haven&amp;rsquo;t given much of an update on what I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on or how I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing - 2020 has definitely been a doozy on staying consistent with the blogging front. However, I have made a lot of progress on developing that skillset by working on a small game project. It&amp;rsquo;s based on a hypothetical sidequest happening for a long-standing D&amp;amp;D campaign I&amp;rsquo;ve been a part of, called Edge of Chaos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in Game Development: Pixel Art</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-09-10-game-dev-pixel-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-09-10-game-dev-pixel-art/</guid>
      <description>Art is hard. I have a lot of respect for people who can do art in a professional capacity, as my level of drawing has barely evolved past stick figure drawings. I used to tell myself that there was no way that I was an artist and that the skills needed to draw were something that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to learn.
Well, at this point I still can&amp;rsquo;t draw. But I took a baby step to becoming more comfortable with art, and started to learn about the mechanics of pixel art in particular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in Game Development: Choosing an Engine</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-08-30-game-dev-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-08-30-game-dev-engine/</guid>
      <description>Probably one of the most important things you&amp;rsquo;ll have to decide before making the game is what engine is most appropriate to do so in. For the longest time, I found making this choice very overwhelming, and I struggled with figuring out which would be most appropriate for me.
There are many choices out there for game development in 2020. There are the engines geared towards people who aren&amp;rsquo;t coders, such as RPG Maker and Game Maker Studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in Game Development: Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-08-27-game-dev-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-08-27-game-dev-beginning/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ll notice I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging as much as of late. That&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that with the current place in my life that I’m at right now that it was worth trying to learn something far meatier that I&amp;rsquo;ve always been interested in - game development.
Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve always had a desire to make a game, but it seemed nearly impossible to do. A few years ago, when I had a &amp;ldquo;great&amp;rdquo; idea, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Practice Cognitive Defusion</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-27-cognitive-defusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-27-cognitive-defusion/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes our brains can ruminate endlessly on narratives we&amp;rsquo;d rather not listen to on a regular basis. A technique to try and soothe these concerns is cognitive defusion. Note: defusion will not necessarily make the thoughts go away and make you feel better. You need to accept thoughts and not try to control/repress them.
However, in general it has helped me. Some exercises that can be used to defuse thoughts are below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dangerous Impact of Social Media</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-24-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-24-social-media/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve become increasingly unimpressed with the impact of social media on our lives. I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself happier using online platforms on a limited basis, so I figured it&amp;rsquo;d be worth talking about why I&amp;rsquo;ve reduced my social media usage so much over the past few years.
It&amp;rsquo;s Designed to be Addictive The goal of mainstream social media apps in 2020 is to keep your attention on the screen for as long as possible, in what is now known as the attention economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Stay Grounded Mentally</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-05-grounding-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-05-grounding-techniques/</guid>
      <description>With the state of the world still being what it is, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to feel disconnected from our bodies. Grounding is a very important practice that we should all use on a regular basis, even when we&amp;rsquo;re not living through history. Below I’ll list a few of my favorite techniques I&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past to stay in the present moment (these can be done in quick succession or separately, depending on personal preferences):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regarding The State of the World in June 2020</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-06-05-end-qualified-immunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-06-05-end-qualified-immunity/</guid>
      <description>My thoughts are effectively summed up by this video here. Hasan does a far better job articulating things than I could hope to in a blog post and what needs to be done for there to be meaningful change.
Do what he says in the video if you care about meaningful change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Statistically: When Data Visualizations Lie to You</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-23-lie-factor-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-23-lie-factor-visualization/</guid>
      <description>If there&amp;rsquo;s one thing I&amp;rsquo;ve learned by going into statistics as a career, it&amp;rsquo;s that it&amp;rsquo;s so easy to &amp;ldquo;lie&amp;rdquo; with data. Visualizations are one of the easiest ways to get away with doing this and tell a story that in all actuality may not be true at all.
Edward Tufte was a statistician and artist, and he was acutely aware of this problem too. He&amp;rsquo;s known for writing books such as The Visual Display of Quantitative Information, which is a classic regarding how to create statistical visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fasting for 24 Hours: First Time Reflections</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-19-fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-19-fasting/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I pulled off a 24 hour fast, where the only thing I consumed in the time frame was water. I&amp;rsquo;ve previously experimented with intermittent fasting in grad school, where there&amp;rsquo;s a specific time frame to eat, and for the rest of the time you only drink water. As I followed the 16:8 approach, I would abstain from food for 16 hours and then eat for 8. But this is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve deliberately pushed past the 16 hour time to go for an entire day&amp;rsquo;s worth of fasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Statistically: The Conjunction Fallacy</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-15-conjunction-fallacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-15-conjunction-fallacy/</guid>
      <description>One of the main boons of me getting involved in statistics is that it taught me a lot about how irrational people&amp;rsquo;s thinking can end up being sometimes. It gave me the idea to create a series of posts to elaborate more on some topics I found useful in my education. My hope is for someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a strong math background to read these posts and start thinking statistically in their everyday lives, even if only a little bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindset: Coursera Notes</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-12-mindset-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-12-mindset-notes/</guid>
      <description>Every now and again I&amp;rsquo;ll dabble in a free online class to see what I can learn from it, usually an MOOC from a site like Coursera or EdX. One I came across recently was called Mindshift, offered by Coursera and hosted by Barbara Oakley. I originally checked out her Coursera class &amp;ldquo;Learning How to Learn&amp;rdquo; between semesters in undergrad and found it very useful to understand the way our brain tries to comprehend things while obtaining my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Sleep Better</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-09-sleep-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-09-sleep-better/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten better at getting consistently good nights of sleep. Here are a few tips you can implement that may help you wake up ready to tackle the world when your alarm goes off:
Wake up and go to bed at the same time every day I know this one is the one I struggle with most personally. Growing up, I was always the type to sleep in on weekends as I never fully rested and awake when I woke up in the mornings for school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can&#39;t Sleep When You&#39;re Dead</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-06-importance-of-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-06-importance-of-sleep/</guid>
      <description>The title of this post is in reference to one of the most frustrating things I&amp;rsquo;ve heard intelligence people say. You cannot logically sleep when you&amp;rsquo;re dead because you need to be alive to sleep. And yet this idea that you can sleep when it&amp;rsquo;s all over lives on. Why? I want to give a few of my thoughts on that:
Workaholic Culture I&amp;rsquo;m speaking primarily towards American culture (I know that work-life balance can be even worse in places like Japan and China), but Americans pride themselves on working hard and doing a good job when they do work hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Practice Psychological First Aid</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-03-psychological-first-aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-03-psychological-first-aid/</guid>
      <description>The goal of providing psychological first aid is to provide acute assistance to someone in crisis. It is a useful skill to have in any day and age, but the uncertainty of our current world makes it more critical than ever. George S. Everly, who works at Johns Hopkins, developed an empirically-based model called RAPID as a framework for people such as first responders to follow. Coursera was offering free certificates for certain classes due to COVID-19, so I decided to go ahead and check this one out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worst Week of My Career</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-02-worst-week-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-02-worst-week-career/</guid>
      <description>This past week has to undoubtedly be the worst week of my young professional career. Because of COVID-19, our analytics department had to make cuts, and some of my favorite coworkers were let go. While I&amp;rsquo;m thankful to still have a job in a freefalling economy and health insurance in a pandemic, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel awful for the people I worked with daily and got to know well over the past few months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging: Why?</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-30-why-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-30-why-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Setting up a blog is an idea I have toyed with for a long time. There was a phase of my life that I used Tumblr and would occasionally write about what&amp;rsquo;s on my mind, but it was never designed as a traditional blog. But I&amp;rsquo;ve now been inspired to finally set up and regularly contribute my words out to the Internet for the people to read, and I figured it was worth talking briefly about why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loneliness: The Silent Killer</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-27-loneliness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-27-loneliness/</guid>
      <description>I listened to Brene Brown&amp;rsquo;s podcast Unlocking Us yesterday and in her most recent episode focused on the topic of loneliness, which made me want to elaborate more on my feelings about the topic.
Throughout my life I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled on and off with loneliness. When I was younger I was quite socially isolated, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel lonely much due to the impact that certain TV shows and video games had on me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Choices: Passions vs Skills</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-26-career-passion-vs-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-26-career-passion-vs-skill/</guid>
      <description>This is the general dilemma I know I went through when I was trying to figure out what degree path to go down. When I&amp;rsquo;ve been at the top of my game in school, most professors have told me I’m smart enough to go down whatever career path I wanted to. While it was nice for so many smart people to think I was also intelligent, it did absolutely nothing for me to help narrow down the avenues I could take my career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Develop Social Skills</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-23-social-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-23-social-skills/</guid>
      <description>Growing up, I used to be very socially awkward. And not the type socially awkward that you see sometimes in media with nerdier women that comes across as being appealing to some. I was socially awkward in the &amp;ldquo;Wow, we want to actively avoid this person&amp;rdquo; way that led to a lot of self-doubt and angst until I was well into my 20s.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a years-long process to get to where I am now socially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful High School Classes I Took</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-22-useful-high-school-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-22-useful-high-school-classes/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking back to my earlier educational experiences, way before I ever thought of attending grad school. I thought about high school, a time of my life I generally don&amp;rsquo;t like to think about very often. I wondered just what happened to me back then that ended up positively informing my behaviors as the adult I am today, and I thought of classes that played a role in that process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Learned By Developing an App</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-21-developing-an-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-21-developing-an-app/</guid>
      <description>During grad school, whenever I had free time I read many books about mental health. (Motivated by necessity - I was struggling to get by some days.) I learned a lot of useful information in these books that I felt would be useful to share with other people in some capacity.
I also realized that getting the job I wanted right out of grad school would be challenging. I identify myself as a generalist over a specialist, so I figured that building an app would be a helpful review of coding outside the programming language of R, which I exclusively used in school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Influential Books I&#39;ve Read</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-20-top-10-transformative-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-20-top-10-transformative-books/</guid>
      <description>These books are going to be listed in the order I initially read them. You may notice a theme in these books regarding human needs, emotions, habit development, and self-acceptance. None of these are specific to my educational experiences, so I expect that most people would benefit from checking these books out.
Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can&amp;rsquo;t Stop Talking by Susan Cain Initially read: 2017</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amanda Park Launches A Blog!</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-19-setting-up-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-19-setting-up-blog/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always toyed with the idea of setting up a blog to write my thoughts out to the world, and now I have mustered up the desire to do so! I have a lot of ideas I&amp;rsquo;m itching to blog about (both personally and professionally), so I look forward to writing for you all!
Thanks to this post for helping me set this up. I can now easily develop posts in Markdown rather than navigate one of the popular blogging platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-01-01-resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-01-01-resume/</guid>
      <description>Amanda Park Greater Grand Rapids Area, Michigan; 607-745-6618; apark24@binghamton.edu; LinkedIn; GitHub
Experience Data Scientist at Spectrum Health, August 2019 - Present
 Forecasted COVID-19 bed utilization for efficient resource planning during a pandemic - example here Found most important symptoms for patients with a positive COVID-19 test using logistic regression, which improved safety measures for staff and patients at-risk for COVID-19 Presented at HDAA Conference in December 2020 discussing an Unsupervised Machine Learning technique for managing at-risk populations Developed financial compensation benchmarks for executives using time series analysis  Data Science Consultant at Internet Leads US, April 2018 - August 2019</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>This is an example of a custom shortcode that you can put right into your content. You will need to add a form action to the the shortcode to make it work. Check out Formspree for a simple, free form service.
Your Name Email Address An email address is required.  Message   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
