<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>health on Amanda Park</title>
    <link>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in health on Amanda Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanda-park.netlify.app/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fasting for 24 Hours: First Time Reflections</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-05-19-fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-05-19-fasting/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I pulled off a 24 hour fast, where the only thing I consumed in the time frame was water. I&amp;rsquo;ve previously experimented with intermittent fasting in grad school, where there&amp;rsquo;s a specific time frame to eat, and for the rest of the time you only drink water. As I followed the 16:8 approach, I would abstain from food for 16 hours and then eat for 8. But this is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve deliberately pushed past the 16 hour time to go for an entire day&amp;rsquo;s worth of fasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Sleep Better</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-05-09-sleep-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-05-09-sleep-better/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten better at getting consistently good nights of sleep. Here are a few tips you can implement that may help you wake up ready to tackle the world when your alarm goes off:
Wake up and go to bed at the same time every day I know this one is the one I struggle with most personally. Growing up, I was always the type to sleep in on weekends as I never fully rested and awake when I woke up in the mornings for school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can&#39;t Sleep When You&#39;re Dead</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-05-06-importance-of-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-05-06-importance-of-sleep/</guid>
      <description>The title of this post is in reference to one of the most frustrating things I&amp;rsquo;ve heard intelligence people say. You cannot logically sleep when you&amp;rsquo;re dead because you need to be alive to sleep. And yet this idea that you can sleep when it&amp;rsquo;s all over lives on. Why? I want to give a few of my thoughts on that:
Workaholic Culture I&amp;rsquo;m speaking primarily towards American culture (I know that work-life balance can be even worse in places like Japan and China), but Americans pride themselves on working hard and doing a good job when they do work hard.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
