<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-improvement on Amanda Park</title>
    <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/tags/self-improvement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-improvement on Amanda Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanda-park.github.io/tags/self-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Committing to Spending Less Time on Social Media</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2021-01-03-reduce-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2021-01-03-reduce-social-media/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve previously made a post about the dangers of social media, which can be seen here. But this post is of a different flavor.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t explicitly talked about this, but in the past, I was addicted to social media. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t ever limited to one social media site, either. Throughout the 2010s, I had phases where I was addicted to a combination of the following at any one time:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Lifelong Learning</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-11-15-lifelong-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-11-15-lifelong-learning/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve read some of my posts you&amp;rsquo;ll know that I&amp;rsquo;ve used online learning tools such as Coursera in the past to learn about topics of interest to me. Being in the field of data science, I know that the best tools for tackling challenging problems are constantly evolving, so it&amp;rsquo;s basically a must that I continue to learn about new findings in the ever-expanding field of data analytics.
One thing my organization did recently that I am incredibly grateful for is offering unlimited access to a site called LinkedIn Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Practice Cognitive Defusion</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-27-cognitive-defusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-27-cognitive-defusion/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes our brains can ruminate endlessly on narratives we&amp;rsquo;d rather not listen to on a regular basis. A technique to try and soothe these concerns is cognitive defusion. Note: defusion will not necessarily make the thoughts go away and make you feel better. You need to accept thoughts and not try to control/repress them.
However, in general it has helped me. Some exercises that can be used to defuse thoughts are below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dangerous Impact of Social Media</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-24-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-24-social-media/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve become increasingly unimpressed with the impact of social media on our lives. I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself happier using online platforms on a limited basis, so I figured it&amp;rsquo;d be worth talking about why I&amp;rsquo;ve reduced my social media usage so much over the past few years.
It&amp;rsquo;s Designed to be Addictive The goal of mainstream social media apps in 2020 is to keep your attention on the screen for as long as possible, in what is now known as the attention economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Stay Grounded Mentally</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-05-grounding-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-05-grounding-techniques/</guid>
      <description>With the state of the world still being what it is, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to feel disconnected from our bodies. Grounding is a very important practice that we should all use on a regular basis, even when we&amp;rsquo;re not living through history. Below I’ll list a few of my favorite techniques I&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past to stay in the present moment (these can be done in quick succession or separately, depending on personal preferences):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindset: Coursera Notes</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-12-mindset-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-12-mindset-notes/</guid>
      <description>Every now and again I&amp;rsquo;ll dabble in a free online class to see what I can learn from it, usually an MOOC from a site like Coursera or EdX. One I came across recently was called Mindshift, offered by Coursera and hosted by Barbara Oakley. I originally checked out her Coursera class &amp;ldquo;Learning How to Learn&amp;rdquo; between semesters in undergrad and found it very useful to understand the way our brain tries to comprehend things while obtaining my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Sleep Better</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-09-sleep-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-09-sleep-better/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten better at getting consistently good nights of sleep. Here are a few tips you can implement that may help you wake up ready to tackle the world when your alarm goes off:
Wake up and go to bed at the same time every day I know this one is the one I struggle with most personally. Growing up, I was always the type to sleep in on weekends as I never fully rested and awake when I woke up in the mornings for school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can&#39;t Sleep When You&#39;re Dead</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-06-importance-of-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-06-importance-of-sleep/</guid>
      <description>The title of this post is in reference to one of the most frustrating things I&amp;rsquo;ve heard intelligence people say. You cannot logically sleep when you&amp;rsquo;re dead because you need to be alive to sleep. And yet this idea that you can sleep when it&amp;rsquo;s all over lives on. Why? I want to give a few of my thoughts on that:
Workaholic Culture I&amp;rsquo;m speaking primarily towards American culture (I know that work-life balance can be even worse in places like Japan and China), but Americans pride themselves on working hard and doing a good job when they do work hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Develop Social Skills</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-23-social-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-23-social-skills/</guid>
      <description>Growing up, I used to be very socially awkward. And not the type socially awkward that you see sometimes in media with nerdier women that comes across as being appealing to some. I was socially awkward in the &amp;ldquo;Wow, we want to actively avoid this person&amp;rdquo; way that led to a lot of self-doubt and angst until I was well into my 20s.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a years-long process to get to where I am now socially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Influential Books I&#39;ve Read</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-20-top-10-transformative-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-20-top-10-transformative-books/</guid>
      <description>These books are going to be listed in the order I initially read them. You may notice a theme in these books regarding human needs, emotions, habit development, and self-acceptance. None of these are specific to my educational experiences, so I expect that most people would benefit from checking these books out.
Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can&amp;rsquo;t Stop Talking by Susan Cain Initially read: 2017</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
