<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>how-to on Amanda Park</title>
    <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/tags/how-to/</link>
    <description>Recent content in how-to on Amanda Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanda-park.github.io/tags/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tips to Write More Effectively</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2021-02-10-quick-writing-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2021-02-10-quick-writing-tips/</guid>
      <description>When I was completing my undergraduate degree, I was known for having strong writing skills. Even if I hated writing essays, I could make a persuasive argument and get the A I wanted.
However, after attending grad school and now being in the workforce, writing a piece that was at least 8 pages and had many sources to back up its argument isn&amp;rsquo;t valuable.
Instead, focused and technical writing prowess is valued.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Practice Cognitive Defusion</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-27-cognitive-defusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-27-cognitive-defusion/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes our brains can ruminate endlessly on narratives we&amp;rsquo;d rather not listen to on a regular basis. A technique to try and soothe these concerns is cognitive defusion. Note: defusion will not necessarily make the thoughts go away and make you feel better. You need to accept thoughts and not try to control/repress them.
However, in general it has helped me. Some exercises that can be used to defuse thoughts are below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Stay Grounded Mentally</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-05-grounding-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-07-05-grounding-techniques/</guid>
      <description>With the state of the world still being what it is, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to feel disconnected from our bodies. Grounding is a very important practice that we should all use on a regular basis, even when we&amp;rsquo;re not living through history. Below I’ll list a few of my favorite techniques I&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past to stay in the present moment (these can be done in quick succession or separately, depending on personal preferences):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Sleep Better</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-09-sleep-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-09-sleep-better/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten better at getting consistently good nights of sleep. Here are a few tips you can implement that may help you wake up ready to tackle the world when your alarm goes off:
Wake up and go to bed at the same time every day I know this one is the one I struggle with most personally. Growing up, I was always the type to sleep in on weekends as I never fully rested and awake when I woke up in the mornings for school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Practice Psychological First Aid</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-03-psychological-first-aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-05-03-psychological-first-aid/</guid>
      <description>The goal of providing psychological first aid is to provide acute assistance to someone in crisis. It is a useful skill to have in any day and age, but the uncertainty of our current world makes it more critical than ever. George S. Everly, who works at Johns Hopkins, developed an empirically-based model called RAPID as a framework for people such as first responders to follow. Coursera was offering free certificates for certain classes due to COVID-19, so I decided to go ahead and check this one out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Develop Social Skills</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-23-social-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.github.io/post/2020-04-23-social-skills/</guid>
      <description>Growing up, I used to be very socially awkward. And not the type socially awkward that you see sometimes in media with nerdier women that comes across as being appealing to some. I was socially awkward in the &amp;ldquo;Wow, we want to actively avoid this person&amp;rdquo; way that led to a lot of self-doubt and angst until I was well into my 20s.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a years-long process to get to where I am now socially.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
