<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career on Amanda Park</title>
    <link>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in career on Amanda Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanda-park.netlify.app/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What I Wish I Knew About R Sooner</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-11-22-r-programming-wish-knew-sooner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-11-22-r-programming-wish-knew-sooner/</guid>
      <description>I was officially exposed to the programming language R when I enrolled in my graduate program in 2017. Three years have passed, and now I feel much more comfortable navigating R than I did when I first started. The way I learned R was very bumpy, and looking back there were a lot of ways I could have improved and expedited developing my skills in the language. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d write about this for anyone also interested in becoming proficient in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Lifelong Learning</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-11-15-lifelong-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-11-15-lifelong-learning/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve read some of my posts you&amp;rsquo;ll know that I&amp;rsquo;ve used online learning tools such as Coursera in the past to learn about topics of interest to me. Being in the field of data science, I know that the best tools for tackling challenging problems are constantly evolving, so it&amp;rsquo;s basically a must that I continue to learn about new findings in the ever-expanding field of data analytics.
One thing my organization did recently that I am incredibly grateful for is offering unlimited access to a site called LinkedIn Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindset: Coursera Notes</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-05-12-mindset-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-05-12-mindset-notes/</guid>
      <description>Every now and again I&amp;rsquo;ll dabble in a free online class to see what I can learn from it, usually an MOOC from a site like Coursera or EdX. One I came across recently was called Mindshift, offered by Coursera and hosted by Barbara Oakley. I originally checked out her Coursera class &amp;ldquo;Learning How to Learn&amp;rdquo; between semesters in undergrad and found it very useful to understand the way our brain tries to comprehend things while obtaining my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Choices: Passions vs Skills</title>
      <link>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-04-26-career-passion-vs-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-park.netlify.app/post/2020-04-26-career-passion-vs-skill/</guid>
      <description>This is the general dilemma I know I went through when I was trying to figure out what degree path to go down. When I&amp;rsquo;ve been at the top of my game in school, most professors have told me I’m smart enough to go down whatever career path I wanted to. While it was nice for so many smart people to think I was also intelligent, it did absolutely nothing for me to help narrow down the avenues I could take my career.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
